William Wong

billycwong19@gmail.com

512-905-4340

linkedin.com/in/williamcwong19

https://william-wong-portfolio.netlify.app/

Summary

MongoDb, React, Express, and Node (MERN) full-stack developer, trained in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, and specializing in Single Page Applications. Capable of building full-stack sites from scratch while utilizing design skills with Figma to build wireframes to high fidelity mock-ups.

Experience



MERN Full-Stack Engineer

Self Employed

Jul 2022 - Present (2 months +)

Conceptualized, built, and maintained several small applications utilizing the MERN stack.

Developed code from back-end to front-end, leaning heavily into React, React Router, sometimes Next.js, and styling with several different CSS libraries, including: Bootstrap, Bulma, DaisyUI, and Styled-Components.

Led front-end team in a small project-based group.

Cashier

The Soup Peddler Real Food & Juice Bar

Aug 2015 - Mar 2022 (6 years 8 months)

Provided friendly and endearing customer service in a fast-paced tightly knit work environment. Created a positive work environment and helped establish a culture inside the restaurant that was inclusive and tolerant, yet firm with our beliefs and self-respect. Maintained a clean and sanitary environment, pre and post Covid.

Drummer

Annabelle Chairlegs

Oct 2016 - Mar 2022 (5 years 6 months)

Drummer for semi-professional rock band. Recorded, performed, and toured as an integral member of the rhythm section. Winner of 2020 Austin Music Video Awards.

Education



UT Austin Boot Camps

Full-Stack Web Development, Computer Science

2022 - 2022

Explored and implemented code in various formats and languages. Learned the MERN stack for creating a website from scratch, back to front.





The Woodlands High School

Licenses & Certifications

Coding Boot Camp Certificate Program - The University of Texas at Austin

React Back to Front - Udemy UC-c1359375-de75-48bf-a05b-31c3e78ed473

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Masterclass - Udemy UC-f672e660-b526-4590-9928-b740a0963fb6

Skills

JavaScript • React.js • Node.js • MongoDB • Express.js • styled-components • Bootstrap • Figma (Software) • Next.js • MySQL